netwheels.co.za 2010-12-20

# Netwheels.co.za: Privacy Statement

**Updated Privacy Statement**

This website (the " ** _Site_** ") is operated by Netwheels.co.za (" ** _Netwheels.co.za_** "). This Privacy Statement (the "Statement") describes Netwheels.co.za's collection, use and disclosure of information practices in connection with the Site. This Statement applies to the national version of the Site, located at [www.Netwheels.co.za](http://www.netwheels.co.za/), as well as to any versions of the Site that Netwheels.co.za operates, including versions or pages that Netwheels.co.za co-brands or private labels with its newspaper and broadcast affiliates, third-party distribution partners and other partners (collectively, " ** _Affiliates_** "). For example, you may have arrived at a co-branded version of the Site from an Affiliate's website, in which case, that Affiliate will be clearly identified at the top of the home page of this Site. In this Statement, Netwheels.co.za refers to those versions of the Site as " ** _Affiliate Versions_**." Please be aware that Netwheels.co.za may share any information you submit through this Site with Affiliates, as described below. During your visit to any Affiliate Version, the Affiliate may independently collect other information from you.

For purposes of clarification, this Statement also describes Netwheels.co.za's collection, use, and disclosure practices with respect to any personally identifiable information and Usage Data (as defined below) that is provided to Netwheels.co.za by any of its third-party distribution partners that display Netwheels.co.za vehicle listings, such as Yahoo!.

This Statement does not describe Netwheels.co.za's collection, use and disclosure of information through means other than this Site (e.g., off-line) or the collection, use and disclosure practices of any Affiliate or other third parties. For information on a third party's information collection, use and disclosure practices, please review the privacy policy on the applicable third party's website. Also, please note that this Site contains links to other websites. Netwheels.co.za is not responsible for the websites, content or privacy practices of any third party. By using this Site, you acknowledge that you have read this Statement and agree that you are subject to the Netwheels.co.za [Terms of Service](http://www.netwheels.co.za/).

**Collection of Personally Identifiable Information**

You are not required to provide any personally identifiable information to visit the Site. Netwheels.co.za automatically collects Usage Data (as described below) and may collect ZIP codes and other information in connection with your use of the Site (e.g., the type of car you are looking for). Netwheels.co.za collects personally identifiable information only when you make it available through your use of the Site. You may be required to provide personally identifiable information to use certain services on this Site, including, but not limited to, the "Email the Dealer/Seller" feature and to purchase and create a "Sell It Yourself" online classified listing (" ** _SIY Ad_** ") and account (" ** _SIY Account_** "). In addition, you may submit personally identifiable information through the Site in other ways, including: (a) participating in online surveys, promotions, contests and sweepstakes; (b) subscribing to newsletters, editorial content, or promotional content sent via email, (c) using the Site's "Feedback" and "More Information" forms; and (d) in connection with other products, services, features, or requests made available through the Site. We also publish toll-free phone numbers for many of the dealerships that list vehicles for sale on the Site. If you dial one of these phone numbers, Netwheels.co.za or a service provider operating on Netwheels.co.za's behalf may record the date, time and length of your call and the phone number from which the call originated, along with other information that may be captured. Any Usage Data (as defined in the next section) and/or personally identifiable information resulting from such calls may be used as described in this Statement. The types of personally identifiable information that you provide will depend on the nature of the submission, but could include your name, address, phone number, email address and credit card information. 

**Passive Information Collection**

The Site automatically collects information and may also customize your visit through technical means, including the following:

**Cookies:** Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer's hard drive by computers (or servers) to identify your computer.

**Web Beacons:** Web beacons (also known as pixel tags, internet tags, clear GIFs, or single-pixel GIFs) are electronic images embedded into a webpage.

**IP Address Logs:** Netwheels.co.za also logs Internet Protocol (IP) addresses - the location of your computer on the internet.

Cookies allow Netwheels.co.za to recognize you when you visit the Site, to personalize your experience and generally to serve you better. For example, if you enter your name, address or Postal code on one of the Site's forms, it may be stored in a cookie so you do not have to enter it again on other forms on the Site. Cookies and web beacons can tell us what advertising you have seen on the Site, which allows Netwheels.co.za to offer you a more diverse selection of advertising information and may also be used together to measure the effectiveness of Netwheels.co.za advertising campaigns. Cookies, web beacons and IP addresses are also used to compile data regarding Site usage (e.g., what website you came from, what pages of the Site you visit, how long you were on the Site, what type of browser you are using, what website you went to). Web beacons may also be included in emails sent by Netwheels.co.za to determine when and if such emails are opened or forwarded. You can disable cookies or otherwise manage them through tools provided with your browser software and with third-party software packages. If you turn off cookies, many of the Site's features will not work as well or at all. Anonymous information regarding use of our Site and services that is collected and/or aggregated by or on behalf of Netwheels.co.za through the use of such technical means or otherwise is referred to in this Statement as " ** _Usage Data_**."

**Information Use**

Personally Identifiable Information. Personally identifiable information collected by Netwheels.co.za through your use of the Site may be stored on servers or in a cookie on your computer and may be used by Netwheels.co.za for any of the following purposes:

·         To confirm or fulfill a request that you make (e.g., in order to send you a price quote or other information you have requested, Netwheels.co.za may share your contact information with a participating Netwheels.co.za dealer and/or manufacturer).

·         To follow up on any request that you have previously made (e.g., Netwheels.co.za may contact you to determine whether the dealer and/or manufacturer responded to your original request).

·         To communicate with you regarding the Netwheels.co.za service (e.g., Netwheels.co.za may send you emails or call you to confirm a price quote request or to notify you that you have received a lead regarding a vehicle you have advertised or to request that you participate in a survey).

·         To send promotional materials, newsletters or other content via email or otherwise, but only if you have indicated that you wish to receive such materials (e.g., Netwheels.co.za will send you auto show newsletters and information regarding how to sell your car on Netwheels.co.za if you have indicated that you wish to receive such newsletters and information). If you no longer wish to receive a particular email newsletter or other promotion from Netwheels.co.za, you must follow the opt-out instructions included in such email newsletters and promotions.

·         To permit third parties (to whom Netwheels.co.za may disclose personally identifiable information specifically for direct marketing purposes) to send you promotional or informational messages, but only if you have first affirmatively agreed to receive such messages.

·         To improve your user experience.

·         To manage Netwheels.co.za's business and its relationships with Affiliates, customers, and other third parties to which Netwheels.co.za may disclose personally identifiable information pursuant to this Statement.

·         For Site administration, analysis, research, development, optimization and other internal purposes, including, without limitation, to compile Usage Data.

**Usage Data:** Usage Data is used by Netwheels.co.za for administrative, analytical, research, optimization and other purposes. For example, Netwheels.co.za may use statistical analyses of Usage Data in order to measure interest in the various areas of the Site, for development purposes and to inform advertisers and partners in aggregate and anonymous terms about consumers who click on their advertising or other messages. IP addresses are also used for systems administration and troubleshooting purposes.

With respect to promotional materials and newsletters that Netwheels.co.za may send from time to time, Netwheels.co.za will not continue to send you such communications if you ask us not to, as described below in the Section entitled "Accessing, Changing or Deactivating Information Collected by Netwheels.co.za." However, you agree that Netwheels.co.za may send to you, and you cannot opt out of, communications of a transactional or relationship nature, including, but not limited to, communications regarding fraudulent or illegal activity, the status of your SIY Account, changes to this Statement or the Netwheels.co.za Terms of Service, as well as communications to confirm, fulfill and follow up on your SIY Account registration or a request submitted through the Site.

**Information Sharing**

Netwheels.co.za may share personally identifiable information that you provide with third parties in the following cases:

  1. _Affiliates_. Netwheels.co.za may share your personally identifiable information with Affiliates on the condition that the Affiliates' disclosure and use of the information is consistent with this Statement.
  2. _Requests_. If you request information or services through the Site, you agree that Netwheels.co.za may share personally identifiable information with third parties as may be necessary to provide such information to or perform such services for you. For example, if you use the Site's "Email the Dealer" form in a vehicle listing to request a price quote from a dealership, Netwheels.co.za will share the information you entered with that dealership (or its designee). If that vehicle listing was provided by an automobile manufacturer on behalf of a dealer, Netwheels.co.za may also share the personally identifiable information you submit as part of the request with the automobile manufacturer and/or its affiliates. Similarly, if through the Site you request additional information from a financial institution, Netwheels.co.za will share your information with that institution. Personally identifiable information also may be included in reports to these third parties, but only when you have intended to submit the information to the third party as described above. After the information is provided to such third parties, the subsequent use or disclosure of such information is subject to those third parties' privacy policies and practices and Netwheels.co.za does not control their subsequent use or disclosure of information.
  3. _Sweepstakes/Promotions_. In the event that you participate in a sweepstakes, contest or other promotion on the Site that is sponsored by Netwheels.co.za and a third party, Netwheels.co.za reserves the right to share personally identifiable information collected in conjunction with the sweepstakes, contest or promotion with the third party. After the information is provided to such third parties, the subsequent use or disclosure of such information is subject to those third parties' privacy policies and practices.
  4. _Direct Marketing_. Except as provided herein, it is Netwheels.co.za's policy not to disclose personally identifiable information of our customers to third parties specifically for the third parties' direct marketing purposes. If you are 18 years of age or older and have affirmatively agreed to receive third-party direct marketing materials, Netwheels.co.za may share personally identifiable information with third parties for direct marketing purposes. Although Netwheels.co.za will notify all third-party direct marketers that the information provided to them is confidential, the subsequent use or disclosure of such information is subject to those third parties' privacy policies and practices.
  5. _Service Providers_. Netwheels.co.za may work with third parties that provide services on its behalf, including, among others, providers of analytical, development, promotional, research, credit card processing, technical and other services. For example, Netwheels.co.za may ask that a third party conduct an online survey or sweepstakes or send newsletters on its behalf. Similarly, if you make a payment to Netwheels.co.za by credit card, Netwheels.co.za may share your personally identifiable information and credit card information with a third party in order to process credit card transactions, or such information may be collected directly by the credit card processing service provider on Netwheels.co.za's behalf. In such cases, Netwheels.co.za asks that the third party maintain your personally identifiable information as confidential and use the information only to perform the services specified by Netwheels.co.za.
  6. _Email List Opt-Outs_. In the event Netwheels.co.za sends promotional emails to you on behalf of third-party advertisers and you inform Netwheels.co.za you wish to opt out of future promotional emails from a particular third party, Netwheels.co.za may share your email address with that third party so the third party may add you to its opt-out lists.
  7. _Other_. Netwheels.co.za expressly reserves the right to release any personally identifiable information or other information you provide to third parties under the following circumstances: (a) when required by law or legal process, (b) to investigate and/or take action against illegal activity, suspected abuse or unauthorized use of the Site, (c) to protect the property or safety of our users or others, (d) to enforce our Terms of Service and (e) in connection with any sale or other transfer of ownership of all or a part of Netwheels.co.za. Further, if you make any personally identifiable information publicly available on the Site, Netwheels.co.za reserves the right to disclose such information to third parties, including, without limitation, insurance companies and Netwheels.co.za's Affiliates and third-party distribution partners.

Please note that the messages that Netwheels.co.za sends to you to confirm, fulfill or follow up on a request may incidentally include promotional material or other content from Netwheels.co.za or its partners. In the case of these messages, Netwheels.co.za is not sharing your personally identifiable information with those third parties. Netwheels.co.za reserves the right to share Usage Data with any third party for any reason.

**Message Boards**

Netwheels.co.za also may offer message boards, bulletin boards, chat rooms, comments areas or other forums (" ** _Forums_** ") on the Site for use by visitors who are 18 years of age or older. Any information you disclose when posting a message in these Forums may become public. You should not include any information in your posting that you do not want other parties to see or use. Moreover, if you post any messages in the Forums that include your email address or phone number you may receive unsolicited emails or calls from third parties.

**Email a Page**

The Site offers you the ability to email certain pages of the Site to a friend or other third party. If you choose to use the "Email a Page" functionality, your name, email address and any message you are allowed to include will be visible to the recipient of the email. The "Email a Page" functionality is for informational purposes only and may not be used for any unlawful purpose, including any harassment or threats. Information collected by Netwheels.co.za through the "Email a Page" functionality shall be used in accordance with this Statement.

**Changes to this Statement**

Any changes to this Statement will be posted on the Site in this location and this Statement will be identified as "Updated". Your continued use of the Site after such notice constitutes acceptance of such changes. In the event of such changes, you can then choose to do nothing, modify the personally identifiable information in your Account, change your email preferences or deactivate your SIY Account.

**Security**

Your personally identifiable information is one of our most valuable assets. We take steps to keep it physically secure in our data centers and it is accessible only to authorized personnel as needed to perform operations governed by this policy. In addition, when Netwheels.co.za collects credit card information from you, Netwheels.co.za uses Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption, the industry standard for protecting privacy in web transactions. Please keep in mind that despite these measures, Netwheels.co.za cannot guarantee or warrant 100 percent security of its servers and databases. Moreover, Netwheels.co.za cannot guarantee that personally identifiable information that you submit through the Site will not be intercepted or otherwise disclosed.

**Children**

Netwheels.co.za believes that it is especially important to protect children's privacy online. Netwheels.co.za does not knowingly collect or use any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13 and Netwheels.co.za does not knowingly provide any personally identifiable information, regardless of its source, to any third party for any purpose whatsoever from visitors younger than 13 years old. No information should be submitted to or posted at Netwheels.co.za by visitors younger than 13 years old.

**Links**

This Site contains links to other sites. While Netwheels.co.za encourages our business partners to adopt privacy policies that build users' trust and confidence in the internet, Netwheels.co.za is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of websites linked to the Site or any third-party products or services offered through the Site.

**Collection of Information by Third Parties**

As noted above, Affiliates and other third parties may collect information about you and your use of the Site through the use of cookies, web beacons and other similar technologies. For example, we work with companies that collect statistical information regarding Site usage and provide related analytical services. We may work with third-party advertising companies that use cookies and web beacons to serve advertisements when you come to the Site and to generate statistics and metrics related to the delivery of such advertisements. We also may work with third-party advertising networks that use cookies, web beacons and other technologies to collect non-personally identifiable information about your visits to and interactions with this Site and other websites in order to provide targeted advertisements to you across their networks of websites (which may or may not include this Site). These third parties also may use this information for determining or predicting the characteristics and preferences of their respective advertising audiences, for measuring the effectiveness of their advertising and for other purposes.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Statement, please email us at [feedback@Netwheels.co.za](mailto:drew@netwheels.co.za?subject=%5Babout%5D%20Privacy%20Statement)

©2010 Netwheels.co.za

Last updated on 30/6/10
